<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Recycler View</string>
    <string name="heading">6 must-watch tech startup movies and shows for budding entrepreneurs</string>
    <string name="news_image">News Image</string>
    <string name="news_heading">6 must-watch tech startup movies and shows for budding entrepreneurs</string>
    <string name="news_desc1">With over 60,000 registered startups in India, the country is the third-largest startup ecosystem in the world after China and the US. There are so many young companies now, it’s resulted in a thriving ‘startup culture’ that everyone wants to be a part of. But creating a company from scratch is no easy feat, especially considering the fact that so many startups fail.\n\n If you are an aspiring entrepreneur who wants to learn from the successes and failures of others, then the following movies/series based on startups can inspire you. These movies/series will show you the realities of starting and running a business, the skills and qualities you need to succeed, and the lessons you can learn from the stories of real-life entrepreneurs.\n\n Released in 2010, The Social Network is a captivating drama that gave us a glimpse into the creation of one of the most influential companies of our time and the complex web of human relationships that drove its success. The movie follows the story of Mark Zuckerberg, played by Jesse Eisenberg, as he creates the social media giant while simultaneously facing lawsuits from former friends and colleagues.\n\n Directed by David Fincher and written by Aaron Sorkin, the film received critical acclaim for its sharp writing, strong performances, and compelling storytelling. It won three Academy Awards, including Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Film Editing, and Best Original Score. The movie is an intriguing exploration of the human psyche, the cost of ambition, and the power of innovation that will stay with you long after the credits roll.\n\n Steve Jobs (2015)\n The 2015 biographical drama film, Steve Jobs, directed by Danny Boyle and written by Aaron Sorkin, follows the life and career of the late Apple co-founder, Steve Jobs. The movie is not a typical biopic, but instead focuses on three pivotal moments in Jobs’ life – the launches of the Macintosh, NeXT, and the iMac – and the personal and professional conflicts he faced leading up to each event.\n The film boasts an impressive cast, including Michael Fassbender as Jobs, Kate Winslet as Joanna Hoffman, and Seth Rogen as Steve Wozniak. Steve Jobs received critical acclaim for its unique storytelling approach and outstanding performances, with many hailing it as one of the best biopics of recent years.\n\n Pirates of Silicon Valley (1999)\n Pirates of Silicon Valley is a 1999 TV movie that dramatizes the rivalry between Steve Jobs of Apple and Bill Gates of Microsoft in the 1970s and 1980s. Based on the book Fire in the Valley by Paul Freiberger and Michael Swaine, the movie depicts the rise and fall of the two tech giants who shaped the personal computer industry. The movie stars Noah Wyle as Jobs and Anthony Michael Hall as Gates, and features cameo appearances from real-life tech personalities.\n\n WeCrashed (2022)\n WeCrashed is a new series on Apple TV+ that tells the true story of WeWork, once one of the most valuable startups in the world, and its charismatic co-founders, Adam and Rebekah Neumann. It will serve as a lesson on what not to do as an entrepreneur.\n The series follows the couple’s vision of creating a global community of entrepreneurs and innovators, and how their ambition, greed, and narcissism led to the company’s spectacular collapse in 2019. Starring Jared Leto and Anne Hathaway as the Neumanns, WeCrashed is a gripping drama that explores the dark side of the tech industry and the human cost of chasing a dream.\n\n The Dropout (2022)\n The Dropout is a biographical drama miniseries that tells the story of Elizabeth Holmes, the founder of Theranos, a biotechnology company that claimed to have developed technology that would revolutionise blood testing.\n The series follows Holmes’ rise and fall as she becomes one of the youngest self-made billionaires in the US, and then faces criminal charges for fraud and conspiracy. The series stars Amanda Seyfried as Holmes, who delivers a disquieting performance that captures the ambition and deception of the character.\n\n Silicon Valley (2014)\n It’s not based on a true story and chances are it won’t inspire any life lessons since it’s a comedy show. But the show has received critical acclaim and multiple Emmy nominations for its witty and sharp writing and humour – and therefore, deserves a mention on this list.\n Silicon Valley parodies the tech industry and its culture. It follows Richard Hendricks, a brilliant but awkward programmer who creates a revolutionary app called Pied Piper. Along with his friends and colleagues, he tries to make his startup successful in the competitive and cutthroat world of Silicon Valley. The show also has many cameo appearances from real-life tech personalities and celebrities.</string>
    <string name="news_desc2">Not every asteroid is able to reach Earth\'s surface or collide with the planet. As soon as any space object enters Earth\'s atmosphere, it starts burning and turns into ashes before small pieces hit the ground. However, if the object turns out to be gigantic, and if it survives the burn, it may pose a danger. Therefore, in order to avoid such situations, NASA monitors the movement of the asteroids and their trajectory on a regular basis. It also shares the details of the asteroids nearing planet Earth via Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL).\n\n  77-foot racing towards Earth today\n As per the latest information, a 77-foot, airplane sized asteroid named 2023 FG5 is zooming towards planet Earth at a rapid speed today, Monday, April 10. The asteroid will come as close as 3.64 million kilometers to the planet. The huge rock is travelling at a speed of 33840 kilometers per hour. As per the information, the asteroid will pass by the planet causing no harm.\n Notably, this is not the only asteroid which will be nearing  today. The other asteroid to zoom past Earth is a 110 foot giant named Asteroid 2023 FT1. It will be close to Earth at a distance of 7.46 million kilometers.\n\n It can be known that the asteroids which are as big as 940 kilometers (about 583 miles) and are placed between Mars and Jupiter, they pose no threat or harm to the planet. "At 5.4 kilometers in diameter, the largest known potentially hazardous asteroid is Toutatis. By comparison, asteroids that populate the main asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter, and pose no threat to Earth, can be as big as 940 kilometers (about 583 miles) across," NASA stated.\n\n</string>
    <string name="news_decs3">Global shipments of personal computers (PCs) fell by 29% in the first quarter of 2023 due to weak demand, excess inventory and a deteriorating macroeconomic climate, with Apple Inc taking the largest hit, market research firm IDC said.\n In the report published Sunday, the International Data Corporation (IDC) said global PC shipments numbered 56.9 million in the first quarter of this year, down from 80.2 million in the same period last year.\n The shipments extended a similar year-on-year decline of 28.1% in the last quarter of 2022.\n Of the top five PC companies analysed in the report, Apple’s Q1 shipments saw the largest drop of 40.5% from the same period in 2022, with Dell Technologies Inc coming in second with a drop of 31%.\n Lenovo Group Ltd, Asustek Computer Inc and HP Inc also faced declines in shipments, the IDC said.\n In February, Apple reported that sales of its Mac computers, which had boomed during the wave of working from home during the pandemic, declined 29% YoY to $7.7 billion in their most recent quarter.\n “The preliminary results also represented a coda to the era of COVID-driven demand and at least a temporary return to pre-COVID patterns. Shipment volume in Q1 2023 was noticeably lower than the 59.2 million units shipped in Q1 2019 and 60.6 million in Q1 2018,” IDC said.\n “The pause in growth and demand is also giving the supply chain some room to make changes as many factories begin to explore production options outside China.”\n Concerns over slowdowns in major economies remain, with recent tumult in the banking sector exacerbating worries that runaway inflation and tight monetary policy would hamper growth and financial investments.\n If the economy is trending upwards by 2024, “we expect significant market upside as consumers look to refresh, schools seek to replace worn-down Chromebooks, and businesses move to Windows 11,” said Linn Huang, research vice president, Devices and Displays at IDC.</string>
    <string name="news_desc4">Here are the top 10 big data technologies that you need to know in the year 2023\n Today, we live in the digital age full of data technologies, when businesses generate and manage massive volumes of data regularly. The term “Big Data” refers to this vast accumulation of organized and unstructured data, which is growing at an exponential rate due to greater digitization. Traditional data processing software, however, is incapable of handling and extracting usable information from Big Data due to its enormous bulk and complexity. As we move ahead to 2023, the good news is that there are a variety of dependable big data solutions to pick from. In this article, we have explained the top 10 big data technologies that you need to know in 2023.\n\n What is Big Data Technology?\n Big data technologies refer to the high volume, and variety of information assets that necessitate creative data processing methods and are cost-effective, for better insight and decision-making rather than traditional data processing methods. Big Data Technologies are software utilities that are primarily intended to analyze, process, and extract information from big datasets with exceedingly complex structures than traditional data processing technologies.\n\n Top Big Data Technologies\n Many big data technologies have recently impacted the market and IT industries. They can be classified into four broad categories, which are as follows: \n\n 1. Apache Hadoop\n The Apache Software Foundation created Apache Hadoop, an open-source, Java-based framework for storing and analyzing large amounts of data. In essence, it provides a distributed storage infrastructure and uses the MapReduce programming methodology to process large amounts of data.\n\n 2. MongoDB\n MongoDB is a cross-platform, open-source document-oriented database designed to store and process huge volumes of data while maintaining high performance, availability, and scalability. MongoDB is classified as a NoSQL database because it does not store or retrieve data in the form of tables.\n\n 3. RainStor\n RainStor is a database management system developed by the RainStor corporation that handles and analyses massive data. De-duplication is a technique used to simplify the storage of vast volumes of data for reference. It eliminates duplicate files due to its ability to organize and store vast volumes of information for reference.\n\n 4. Cassandra\n Cassandra is a distributed open-source NoSQL database that allows for in-depth analysis of several sets of real-time data. It allows for high scalability and availability without sacrificing performance. CQL is used to interface with the database.\n\n 5. Presto\n Facebook created Presto, an open-source SQL query engine that allows for interactive query analysis on massive amounts of data. This distributed search engine allows for quick analytics searches on data sources ranging in size from gigabytes to petabytes. This technology allows you to query data exactly where it is, without having to move it to a separate analytics system.\n\n 6. RapidMiner\n RapidMiner is a powerful open-source predictive analytics data mining application. It’s a strong data science platform that enables data scientists and big data analysts to quickly analyze their data. It supports model deployment and model operation in addition to data mining. You will have access to all of the data preparation tools and machine learning you require to have an effect on your company operations with this solution.\n\n 7. ElasticSearch\n Elasticsearch, which is based on Apache Lucene, is a distributed, open-source, analytics, modern search engine that allows you to index, search, and analyze data of all types. Log analytics, operational intelligence, security intelligence, full-text search, and business analytics are some of its most common use cases.\n\n 8. Kafka\n Apache Kafka is a popular open-source event store and streaming technology written in Java and Scala by the Apache Software Foundation. Thousands of organizations rely on the platform for streaming analytics, high-performance data pipelines, data integration, and mission-critical applications.\n\n 9. Splunk\n Splunk is a scalable, sophisticated software platform that finds, analyzes, and visualizes machine-generated data from websites, applications, sensors, and devices, among other sources, to offer metrics, diagnose problems, and gain insight into corporate processes. Splunk captures, indexes, and correlates real-time data into a searchable repository that can be used to generate Reports, Alerts, Graphs, Dashboards, and Visualizations.\n\n 10. KNIME\n KNIME, commonly referred to as Konstanz Information Miner, is a platform for data analytics, integration, and reporting that is free and open-source. KNIME is not only intuitive and open, but it also actively absorbs new ideas and advancements to make data interpretation and constructing data science processes and reusable components as simple and accessible as feasible.\n\n Disclaimer: The information provided in this article is solely the author/advertisers’ opinion and not an investment advice – it is provided for educational purposes only. By using this, you agree that the information does not constitute any investment or financial instructions by Analytics Insight and the team. Anyone wishing to invest should seek his or her own independent financial or professional advice. Do conduct your own research along with financial advisors before making any investment decisions. Analytics Insight and the team is not accountable for the investment views provided in the article.</string>
    <string name="news_desc5">An Air India aircraft that was to operate a flight from the national capital to San Francisco suffered a technical issue before take off and returned to the stand on Monday morning, sources said.\n The airline replaced the aircraft and later the flight took off for San Francisco.\n There were little over 200 passengers onboard, the sources added.\n According to the sources, the plane had pushed back and returned to the stand before take off due to the technical issue. Later, the passengers were accommodated in another aircraft.\n There was no immediate statement from Air India.</string>
    <string name="news_desc6">With the advent of the Apple Watch, smartwatches have become the primary health monitoring devices for many users. From real-time ECG to measuring body temperature, the Apple Watch offers a host of features that would otherwise require expensive medical devices. According to a recent patent filed by Apple, the company could be looking to add more functionality to its watch, and this time via the strap.\n One advantage of owning multiple generations of the Apple Watch is the fact that you can easily swap between straps. The latest patent filed by Apple suggests that the company might soon introduce a smart strap that could recognize hand gestures by measuring the electric signals using the built-in electrodes on the strap.\n As per the pictures in the patent file, the new technology could sense various hand movements such as up, down, rotation (both clockwise and counterclockwise), and is even said to be capable of measuring lateral motions. However, note that Apple has just filed for the patent and is yet to receive approval from the US Patent and Trademark Office.\n The possible applications of this technology include improved accessibility features for physically challenged users, accurate workout tracking, and improved gesture recognition. It could even be used to recognize the type of workout without needing user input. Given that the patent is still under approval, one might have to wait at least a few years to see this tech in action.</string>
</resources>